Guide to the Abraham Unger Papers TAM.157
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Abraham Unger Papers
1936-1980
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Unger, Abraham, 1899-1975
TAM.157
13.5 Linear Feet in 13 record cartons and 1 manuscript box
Abraham Unger (1899-1975) was a lawyer, Communist, a founder and officer of the National Lawyers Guild and leader of its New York City Chapter, and beginning in 1948, partner in the law firm of Freedman and Unger. His defendants included the Communist Party USA, various state-level Party organizations, individual Communists and progressive activists, radical and/or Communist-associated labor unions and their leaders and activists, Puerto Rican nationalists, and fellow lawyers charged with contempt and other crimes in connection with their defense of radicals. The collection contains personal and legal correspondence; legal documents pertaining to cases handled by Unger andd those of interest to him; published and unpublished writings; records of the National Lawyers Guild and of its New York City chapter; subject files; and clippings and printed ephemera.
Historical/Biographical Note
Abraham Unger (1899-1975) was a lawyer, Communist, a founder and officer of the National Lawyers Guild and leader of its New York City Chapter, and beginning in 1948, partner in the law firm of Freedman and Unger. His defendants included the Communist Party USA, various state-level Party organizations, individual Communists and progressive activists, radical and/or Communist-associated labor unions and their leaders and activists, Puerto Rican nationalists, and fellow lawyers charged with contempt and other crimes in connection with their defense of radicals. Unger was a graduate of the New York University Law School. As a member of the International Labor Defense, he took part in the preparation of the defense of nine young African American men convicted of rape in Scottsboro, Alabama in 1931. Unger also defended the first twelve Communist Party USA top leaders indicted under the Smith Act in 1949 (for conspiring to advocate the violent overthrow of the U.S. government), and was himself indicted for contempt in 1953 for refusing to answer questions from Senator Joseph McCarthy before the U.S. Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations, including whether or not he headed the Party's section for professionals. Unger also defended Puerto Rican nationalist Juan Bernardo Lebron who was charged as a conspirator in the 1954 attack on the US House of Representatives, and petitioned for the commutation of Oscar Collazo’s life sentence for his 1952 attempted assassination of Harry Truman.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Elizabeth Starcevic and Nick Unger in 1995. The accession number associated with these materials is 1950.134. Elizabeth Starcevic sent an additional 3 boxes of Unger's papers related to Puerto Rican political prisoners in 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2017.001.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into six series. Files in series I-V are arranged alphabetically by topic or document type. Matierials in Series VI: 2016 Accretion have not been arranged by an archivist and are in the order in which they were received by the donor.
The series in this collection are as follows:
Series I: Biographical Materials, Correspondence, and Writings; Series II: Cases; Series III: National Lawyers Guild; Series IV: National Lawyers Guild. New York City Chapter; Series V: Subject Files; Series VI: 2016 Accretion
Scope and Contents
The collection contains personal and legal correspondence; legal documents pertaining both to cases handled by Abraham Unger and those of interest to him; published and unpublished writings; records of the National Lawyers Guild and of its New York City chapter; subject files; and clippings and printed ephemera.
Notable correspondents include lawyers Bella Abzug, Ben Margolin and Samuel Rosewein. Notable clients represented (usually as defendants) include: The American Communications Association, attorney Maurice Braverman and Abraham Isserman (contempt / disbarment in connection with Smith Act case activity); the Communist Party state organizations of Alabama, Colorado, Georgia, Louisiana, New York, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Texas, Virginia, and Washington; Gerhart Eisler (passport and deportation); and (on behalf of Curran), Andrew Furuseth, President of International Seamen's Union of America v. Joseph Curran, Joseph, Chairman Provisional Strike Committee (1936), Willie McGee, and Unger's son Nicholas. The National Lawyers Guild series includes correspondence of Unger and other members, minutes of the executive board and of several committees, including that overseeing the publication of the Lawyers Guild Review, convention materials, and statements and resolutions and other internal documents. The NLG New York City Chapter series contains executive board minutes and correspondence, files on New York State court reform, committee and general records, membership lists, and resolutions and statements.
The Subject Files series covers numerous organizations, causes, events, and some individuals, with an overall focus on civil rights and liberties and laws and legislation. Files include: the American Bar Association, American Birobidjan Committee, Anti Red Ordinance (Birmingham, AL), Ben Davis Bail Committee, Oscar Collazo (Puerto Rican nationalist), the Columbia University Student Strike of 1968, the Committee to abolish HUAC (U.S. House Committee on Unh-American Activities), Council on African Affairs, Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, Bill Eption (Puerto Rican nationalist), International Labor Defense, Lawyers Committee to End the War in Vietnam, the New York State's 1949 "Feinberg" law (providing for the dismissal of teachers belonging to "subversive" organizations), and the Trade Union Committee to Defend Louis Weinstock.
Materials added to the collection in 2016 predominantly include documents related to Unger’s legal defense of members of the Puerto Rican Independence Movement. They include Unger’s notes and legal documents related to the cases of Oscar Collazo and Juan Bernardo Lebron, both of whom he defended in the 1950s. The accretion also contains clippings, ephemera, and articles related to the Puerto Rican Independence Movement and its leader Pedro Albizu Campos. Other materials in this accretion include Unger’s personal correspondence between 1947 and 1952 and papers related to Unger’s involvement in the Communist Party of the United States.
Freedom of speech -- United States.; Communists -- United States.; Minutes (administrative records); Manuscripts for publication.; African Americans -- Civil rights -- United States.; Law -- United States -- Cases.; Communist trials -- United States.; Legal correspondence.; Correspondence; Communism -- United States -- 20th century.; Legal documents.; Civil rights -- United States.; Lawyers -- Political activity -- United States.; Notes.; Anti-communist movements -- United States.; Puerto Rico -- History -- Autonomy and independence movements; Legal assistance to prisoners -- United States.; United States. Congress. House. |b Committee on Un-American Activities; Lamont, Corliss, 1902-1995.; Nathan, Otto, 1893-1987.; Abzug, Bella S., 1920-1998; McGee, Willie, 1915-1951; National Lawyers Guild. New York City Chapter; National Lawyers Guild; Unger, Abraham, 1899-1975; United States. Constitution. 1st Amendment; American Communications Association; Curran, Joseph Edwin, 1906-1981; Isserman, A. J. (Abraham J.); Eisler, Gerhart; Unger, Nicholas; Teachers' Union of the City of New York; Davis, Benjamin J. (Benjamin Jefferson), 1903-1964; Rosenwein, Samuel; Margolis, Ben; United States. |t Alien Registration Act, 1940; Weinstock, Louis, 1903-1994
- Series I: Abraham Unger Biographical Material, Correspondence, and Writings, 1934-1972
  - Certificates to Practice Law (Various Jurisdictions), 1948-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Abzug, Bella, 1957, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Black Question, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Board of Immigration Appeals, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Civil Rights Congress, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence:Columbia University Strike, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Committee to Abolish the House Committee on Un-American Activities (National, New York Council), 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Defense of Lawyers Representing Communist Leaders, 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Freedman, David, 1937-1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Halper, Solomon, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Margolin, Ben, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: McCarthyism, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Mundt-Nixon Bill, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: National Broadcasting Company, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Parker, Et al. v. County of Los Angeles, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Rosenwein, Samuel, 1956-1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Rosenwein, Samuel, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Third Parties, 1948-1962 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Third Party, Mindel, Mrs. Jacob (Pop), Oct 26, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Vietnam, 1958-1966 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Wilson, James, 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Notebooks: McCarthyism, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Printed Ephemera (Invitations to Dinners, Memorials, etc.), 1962-1972 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - World War 2: Military Service and Veteran Administration, 1943-1950 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Writings Attributed to Abraham Unger, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Writings Attributed to Abraham Unger, 1942-1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Writings Attributed to Abraham Unger: Fragments, Incompete Manuscripts, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Writings: Black Question, 1942-1968 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Writings: Book Reviews, 1941, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Writings: Communist Party, 1948-1967 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Writings: Editorials, 1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Writings: "Federalism" (includes correspondence with International Association of Democratic Lawyers), 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Writings: Handwritten, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Writings: Handwritten, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Writings: Handwritten Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Writings: Handwritten - Vietnam, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Writings: Hungarian Revolution, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Writings: Letters to Editors, 1934-1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Writings: McCarthyism, 1951-1956 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Writings: Speeches, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Writings: "The Status of Civil Liberties in 1953 - A Report of the National Committee" Presented at the 1953 Convention of the National Lawyers Guild (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Series II: Cases, 1936-1974
  - Alexander, Frank Edward v. United States of America, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - American Communications Association; Selly, Joseph P. Defendence: NLG NYC Chapter Amicus Curiae, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Anastaplo, George: Application for Admission to the Bar of Illinois; Petition the Denial of the Application for Admission, 1954-1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Beck, Jay: Report of Samuel R. Wachtell to the Executive Committee of the National Lawyers Guild, New York City Chapter, 1954-1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Blatz, Andrew A. (Plaintiff-Respondent) v. Ward, Diana and Evelyn Preston (Defendants-Appelants), 1936 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Braverman, Maurice L.: Disbarment (Smith Act Defense Attorney), 1952-1955, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Braverman, Maurice: Reinstatement to Practice Law, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Burrell, Herman D. (Plaintiff) v. Moran, John P. (Defendant), 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Busch Strike Cases, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cohen, Albert Martin (Petitioner) v. Hurley, Denis M. (Respondent), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania v. Hechtman, Evelyn; Ruth Martin; Jennie Getman, and Geraldine Ivens, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Communist Party USA v. Subversive Activities Control Board, 1955, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Communist Party State Cases, Alabama (Correspondence), 1948 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Communist Party State Cases, Colorado (Correspondence), 1948-1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Communist Party State Cases, Colorado (Legal Documents - Including Wertheimer, Nancy; Jane Rogers; Irving Blau; Arthur Bary; Paul Meir Kleinboard), 1948-1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Communist Party State Cases, Georgia (Correspondence), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Communist Party State Cases, Louisiana (Correspondence and Legal Documents - Including Himmaugh, Robert Edgar; Jackson, James E.) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Communist Party State Cases, New York: Feiner, Irving, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Communist Party State Cases, Ohio (Correspondence), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Communist Party State Cases, Pennsylvania (Correspondence and Legal Documents - Including Musmanno, Michael A.; Dorothy Albert; Matthew B. McAndrew), 1948-1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Communist Party State Cases, Texas: Estes, Fred, 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Communist Party State Cases, Virginia, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Communist Party State Cases: Washington (Includes Gundlach, Ralph; Edward H. Lauer; Herbert J. Phillips), 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Communist Party State Cases, Wisconsin (Correspondence), 1946 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Confidential, Inc. (Plaintiff) v. Summerfield, Arthur J.(Defendant), 1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Deportation Cases (Unidentified), undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Eisler, Gerhardt: Deportation and Passport Case, 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Fay, Charles: President of the Amalgamated Machine Instrument and Metal Local 475, United Electrical Radio and Machine Workers of America v. Douds, T. Charles: Regional Director of the National Labor Relations Board, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Fight for Free Enterpise, Inc. v. Philip Murray, et. al., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - The Fortas Case, 1969, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Furuseth, Andrew, President of International Seamen's Union of America v. Curran, Joseph, Chairman Provisional Strike Committee, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Gomez, Mateo (Appellant) v. The City of Miami (Appellee): Judgment Reversal, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Harisiades, Peter: Deportation Case, 1958, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Harper, Julius Van (Petitioner) v. Wall, Cornelius A. Sheriff of the County of Middlesex, State of New Jersey (Defendant), undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities: Hollywood Ten, Contempt of Citation, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Isserman, Abraham J.: Disbarment, 1951, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Jackson, Clarence; Lorenzo Reed (Relator-Appellants) v. Ruthazer, Herman J., Warden of City Prison, Borough of Manhattan (Respondent-Appellee), 1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Johnson, Leon (Appellant) v. Dye, Charles L., Warden of Allegheny County Jail (Appellee), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee (Plaintiff) v. Clark, C. Tom, et al. (Defendants), 1948 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Kinoy, Arthur (Appellant) v. District of Columbia (Appellee), Jul 29, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Knaisky, Alex: In the Matter of the Application for Naturalization, March 28, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Konigsberg, Raphael v. The State Bar of California, 1956, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Loyalty Board Cases, 1940-1948, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - McCarran Act, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - McGee, Willie v. Mississippi (Clippings, Correspondence, Manuscripts, Notes), 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - McGee, Willie v. Mississippi (Legal Documents), 1948-1949, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - McGee, Willie v. Mississippi (Legal Documents), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - McGee, Willie v. Mississippi (Legal Documents), 1951-1952, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Medina, Harold Judge: Sentencing the Five Lawyers for Protecting Communists, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Middlebrooks, Sylvester's Application for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Minor, Robert (Smith Act), 1948 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Mitchell, David: Draft Register, 1966-1969, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Muste, A. J.: Disorderly Conduct Case (Vietnam War Protest?) (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Nathan, Otto v. Dulles, John Foster, Secretary of the State, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - National Lawyers Guild v. Attorney General Brownell, 1953-1955, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - New York University v. Students for a Democratic Society, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    McGee, Willie, 1915-1951
  - New York University v. Students for a Democratic Society, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Peekskill Riot (Correspondence, Legal Documents), 1949-1951, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Petersen, Norman Lloyd (Plaintiff) v. Ramsey, Clark (Defendant): Order Denying Defendants Motion to Dismiss Nature of the Case, Commentary, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Phillips, Herbert J. v. United States of America, 1953-1956 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Popper, Martin v. House of Un-American Committee (HUAC), undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Rabinowitch, Germina: Application for Admission as a Returning Resident, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Reynolds, Ruth M.: Puerto Rican Prisoner's Case, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Robeson, Paul (Plaintiff) v. Fanelli, George M. (Defendant), undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Rockwell and Lincoln Case (American Nazi Party), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Rosenbergs Case: Judge Rifkin's Article, 1972-1974, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Rosenbergs Case (Legal Documents, Correspondence), 1951-1953, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Rosenbergs Case/Morton Sobell, 1953-1955, 1973, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Sack, Alexander v. New York University, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Seale, Bobby, Chairman of the Black Panther Party (Plaintiff) v. Hoffman, Julius J. (Defendant), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Self-Incrimination Cases, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Smith Act Cases, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Smith Act, Maryland: Frankfeld, Philip and Meyers, George A. (Plaintiffs) v. Hammond, Hall, Attorney General, et al. (Defendants), undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Smith Act, Maryland: United States of America v. Frankfeld, Philip et al.: "Court's Charge to the Jury", undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - The State of New York v. Blair, Arthur; Edward Drolette, et al., undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - The State of New York (Plaintiff) v. Rein, Richard (Defendant), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - The State of New York, ex rel.Mollie Portnoy (Relator-Respondent) v. Ann Strasser, Known as Ann De Carava (Defendent-Appellant), undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - The State of New York v. Unger, Nicholas and Wolfe, Robert (Clippings), 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - The State of New York v. Unger, Nicholas and Wolfe, Robert (Correspondence), 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - The State of New York v. Unger, Nicholas and Wolfe, Robert (Handwritten Notes), 1970, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - The State of New York v. Unger, Nicholas and Wolfe, Robert (Legal Documents), 1970, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - The State of New York v. Unger, Nicholas and Wolfe, Robert (Legal Documents), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Tanner,Murdock and McElroy, Clarence v. United States of America: Conspiracy to Violate Internal Revenue Laws, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Thompson, Francis J., Instructor in the Public Speaking Department, City College, New York: Charged with Being a Member of the Communist Party (Appeal), 1948 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - The Trenton Six Case, 1949-1950, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America, CIO (Plaintiffs) v. Lilienthal, David E. (Defendants), Aug 24, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America v. US Army and Navy Departments, Aug 24, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - United States of America v. Caughlan, John, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - United States of America v. Christoffel, Harold Roland, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - United States of America v. Davis, Benjamin Jr., undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - United States of America (Plaintiff) v. Doe, John (Defendant): Motion for Judgment of Acquittal, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - United States of America v. Dolsen, James H. (Defendant): Proceedings, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - United States of America v. Dubois, W.E.B. et al., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - United States of America (Plaintiff) v. Eisdorfer, Noel Stanley (Defendant): Memorandum and Order, Jun 24, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - United States of America (Appellee) v. Eugene, Dennis et al. (Defendants-Appellants), 1949 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - United States of America v. Foster, William Z., et al., undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - United States of America v. Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - United States of America v. Franklin, Irwin, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - United States of America v. Lamont, Corliss, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - United States of America (Appellant) v. Lamont, Corliss; Unger, Abraham; Shadowitz, Albert (Appelles), 1955-1956, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - United States of America v. Mitchell, David (Defendant), 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - United States of America v. Morford, Richard: Contempt of the House Committee on Un-American Activities, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - United States of America v. Mulcahy, Michael F., Sheriff of Cook County, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - United States of America v. Peace Information Center, 1951, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - United States of America v. Popper, Martin, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - United States of America (Appellee) v. Sacher, Harry; Richard Gladstein; George W. Crockett; Louis F. McCabe, Jr.; Abraham J. Isserman; Eugene Dennis ((Appellants), undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - United States of America v. Shadowitz, Albert, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - United States of America v. Sharpnack, Gerald H.: Charges of Sex Crimes Committed at the Randolph Air Force Base, Texas, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - United States of America v. Unger, Abraham: Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - United States of America (Appellant) v. Unger, Abraham (Appellee), 1953, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - United States of America v. Vietnam Demonstrators, 1966-1968, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Wilkinson, Frank (Appellant) v. United States of America (Appellee): Brief for the Petitioner, Brief for Appellant, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Wilson, James (Petitioner-Appellant) v. Ryan, Timothy, Warden of City Prison, the Bronx (Respondant): Handwritten Documents, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Wilson, James (Petitioner-Appellant) v. Ryan, Timothy, Warden of City Prison, the Bronx (Respondant): Brief of Petitioner-Appellant for Supreme Court Respondant, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Wilson, James (Petitioner-Appellant) v. Ryan, Timothy, Warden of City Prison, the Bronx (Respondant): Legal Documents, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Wilson, James (Petitioner-Appellant) v. Ryan, Timothy, Warden of City Prison, the Bronx (Respondant): Legal Documents, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 4)